Geoffrey T. Perrin

Github: github.com/gperrin12 | geoffperrin@gmail.com | 734.674.5481 | New York City, NY

SUMMARY:

I'm an experienced data scientist and a recent recipient of a master's degree at NYU focusing on using machine learning to solve urban problems.

Specialties: Machine Learning; Random Forest Regression and Classification; Neural Networks / DNN, CNN, and RNN; Image Processing; Computer Vision; Spatial Analysis; Crowd Sourced Data Collection; Cloud Computation; Time Series Analysis; Fourier Transformations; Natural Language Processing; Sentiment Analysis; Big Data / Distributed Computing.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Programing Languages: R, Python, SAS, Stata, SQL

Programing Tools: Pandas, GeoPandas, NumPy, NLTK, TextBlob, Jupyter, Tableau, ArcGIS, Alteryx, Amazon EC2, Amazon RDS for PostgreSQL, Computer Vision (OpenCV), Deep Learning (TensorFlow, Keras), PySpark

EXPERIENCE:

Bloomberg Associates

New York City, NY

Data Scientist

August 2017 - Present

- Built Tableau dashboards for the city of Bogotá Oversight Department, greatly increasing their ability to respond to citizen complaints. Presented results in Spanish in Bogotá, and in English at Bloomberg's D4GX Conference.
- Using NLP and sentiment analysis to improve classification of complaint data for Bogotá.
- NYU Center for Urban Science and Progress

New York City, NY

Graduate Student / Graduate Research Assistant MacArthur Fellow

September 2016 - August 2017

- Improved the granularity of predicting household waste generation for the Department of Sanitation New York (DSNY) by building a neural network model with an R-squared nearing 0.87.
- Improved NYPD's ability to predict the propensity for a neighborhood to report a shooting incident by building a random forest classification model.
- Capstone project reduces city costs by 95% in assessing bike lane quality. Accomplished through computer vision algorithms, crowd sourced data collection, and cloud computing.
- Detroit Land Bank Authority

Detroit, MI

Bloomberg Fellow

July 2016 - May 2017

- Reduced foreclosed home pipeline sorting time by 95% by building random forest classification model, which predicts whether or not a home is occupied, with 97% accuracy.
- Reduced decision making time in whether or not a Detroit Land Bank owned property should be demolished by 90% by building random forest classification model, with 96% accuracy.

Levi Strauss & Co.

San Francisco, CA

Senior Analyst

July 2013 - July 2016

 Saved LS&Co. \$5 million as measured by sales not lost due to stockouts by building ARIMA time series forecasting models and presenting results through Tableau dashboards.

Acumen
San Francisco, CA

Quantitative Analyst II

January 2012 - July 2013

• Reduced the time taken in bringing cases to court by DOJ lawyers by 50% by building a logit classifier model detecting providers committing Medicare fraud.

EDUCATION:

Masters of Science in Urban Informatics

August 2017

New York University - New York, NY

 Bachelor of Science in Economics, Financial Mathematics University of Michigan – Ann Arbor, MI May 2009